Guide to the Pierre Jay Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Pierre Jay papers
1920-1930
1925-1930
MS 660
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
8
(22 boxes)
Correspondence, reports, and other papers of Pierre Jay, banker and Deputy Agent General for Reparations in Berlin from December, 1926 to May, 1930. These papers deal primarily with the Dawes Plan for collecting reparations from Germany following World War I and consist mainly of reports, minutes, and printed materials related to the work of the Economic Service section of the Transfer Committee.
Jay, Pierre, 1870-1949
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Pierre Jay, 1933.
Arrangement
Arranged in six series: I. General Correspondence. II. Personal and Memorabilia. III. Weekly Credit and Financial Summary. IV. Documents. V. Minutes of Meetings of the Transfer Committee. VI. Printed Materials.
Scope and Contents
The Yale University Library's collection of Pierre Jay Papers is rather limited in scope: chronologically speaking, it comprises material dating almost entirely from the time of Jay's assignment in Berlin. The collection has been arranged in six series, as follows: I. General Correspondence (part of l box) - There are seven topical subdivisions, the largest of which comprises congratulatory letters received by Jay at the time of his appointment to the post of Deputy Agent General in Berlin. (A "List of Correspondents" is also included.) II. Personal and Memorabilia (part of 1 box). III. Weekly Credit and Financial Summary (4 boxes) - Mimeographed reports issued by the Economic Service section of the Transfer Committee. Filed monthly, January 1925 - April 1930, with indexes. IV. Documents (6 boxes) - Mimeographed materials issued by the Economic Service section of the Transfer Committee. Filed in original numerical order. [Documents Nos. 3, 5, 6, 10, 35, 69, 106, 126, 130, 132, 187, 202 321, 322, 325, 327, 332 are missing.] V. Minutes of Meetings of the Transfer Committee (7 boxes) - Incomplete set of mimeographed sets of notes, with annexes and/or appendices. VI. Printed Materials (2 boxes).
Biographical / Historical
Pierre Jay: banker; vice-president of the Old Colony Trust Company of Boston, 1903; later vice-president of the Bank of Manhattan Company and chairman of the board of directors and Federal Reserve Agent of the Federal Reserve Bank of New York; Deputy Agent General for Reparation Payments in Berlin, 1926-1930.
Pierre Jay, a direct descendant of the first Chief Justice of the United States, was born in Warwick, New York, in 1870. He prepared for Yale at Hopkins and Groton and received his B. A. in 1892. In 1903 he was elected vice president of the Old Colony Trust Company of Boston. Subsequently he became vice president of the Bank of Manhattan Company, and chairman of the board of directors and Federal Reserve Agent of the Federal Reserve Bank of New York. Jay had already traveled extensively in Europe before being appointed Deputy Agent General for Reparation Payments in December 1926. He was posted to Berlin where he remained until May 1930. He then returned to New York to become chairman of the board of the Fiduciary Trust Company, a post he held until his retirement in 1945. He died in 1949.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
World War, 1914-1918 -- Reparations; Europe; Germany; United States -- Foreign relations; Bankers; Altschul, Frank, 1887-1981; Barbour, James R.; Dillard, J. H. (James Hardy), 1856-1940; Garrison, Lloyd K. (Lloyd Kirkham), 1897-1991; Garrison, Lloyd Kirkham, 1897-; Hand, Augustus Noble, 1869-1954; Jay, Pierre, 1870-1949; Kent, Fred I., 1869-1954; Peabody, Endicott, 1857-1944; Polk, Frank Lyon, 1871-1943; Young, Owen D., 1874-1962
- Correspondence, Series I
  - re: Business and personal affairs (30), (1926-1927) (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - re: Brearley School affairs (5), (1926-1927) (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - re: Groton School affairs (9), (1920, 1926) (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - re: Metropolitan Museum of Art affairs (4), (1920) (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - re: Club memberships, etc. (4), (1925-1926) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - re: Miscellaneous committees and boards (6), (1926-1927) (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - re: Congratulatory letters (49)(1926-1927) (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - LIST OF CORRESPONDENTS
    - Adams, Lewis G.
      General
      See: box 1, folder 7
    - Altschul, Frank
    - Barbour, James R.
    - Barnard College
      See: box 1, folder 6
    - Berle [?], Howard F.
      See: box 1, folder 1
    - Boies, W. J.
    - Bowers, Thomas W.
    - Breck, Joseph
      See: box 1, folder 4
    - Bu____, W. Randolph
    - Call, A. L.
      See: box 1, folder 3
    - Cann, H. V.
    - Case, G. B.
    - Close, F. N. B.
    - Comstock, L. K.
    - Curtis, J. F. (?)
    - Davis, Frances
      See: box 1, folder 2
    - Davis, Malcolm W.
      See: box 1, folder 5
    - Dawes, Rufus C.
    - Denison, J. H.
    - Dillard, J. H.
    - Doyle, Nicholas A.
    - Everitt, John D.
    - Fidelity and Deposit Company
    - Fifth Avenue Bank
    - Gardner, W.
    - Garretsee, J. O.
    - Garrison, Lloyd
    - Gilder, J. B.
    - Haight, Charles S.
    - Hand, Augustus N.
    - Hatch, Mansfield, and Company
    - Holdsworth, J.
    - Holmes, R. A.
    - Holter, Edwin O.
    - Illinois Bankers Association
    - Institut Für Auswärtege Politik
    - Jay, Ellen [Mrs. Lloyd Garrison]
    - Jay, Jack
    - Jay, Louisa [Mrs. Pierre Jay]
    - Kent, F. I.
    - Lander, Ethel
    - Lawrence, James
    - Lawyers Mortgage Company
    - Leffingwell, R. [?]
    - McLean, Robert
    - Martin, Charlotte
    - Martin, George W.
    - Masson, R.
    - Mattocks, R. L.
    - Mellick, Anna C.
    - Miller, Helen C.
    - Monahan, Margaret B.
    - Neilson, Jason A.
    - Newton, Oscar
    - Packard, Mary Storrs
    - Peabody, Endicott
    - Peabody, John Foster
    - Penniman, Elisha
    - Perrin, John
    - Perrin, Lester W.
    - Pike, H. H. Jr.
    - Platt, Edmund
    - Platten, J. Homer
    - Polk, Frank
    - Pope, Emily A.
    - Post, Bertram
    - Post, Wilfred M.
    - Potter, William C.
    - Rogers, Edmund P.
    - Rogers, Charles B.
    - Reeves, Owen D. Jr.
    - Sachs, Charles
    - Sanger, Prentice
    - Seoul Mining Company
    - Sifton, Praed and Company
    - Simmons, E.
    - Smith, Charles
    - Snyder, Carl
    - Spencer, Bird W.
    - Speyer, James
    - Stanley, Howard
    - Stedman, John
    - Strong, Benjamin
    - Teller, J. M.
    - Treman, Charles E.
    - Treman, Robert H.
    - Trowbridge, A. B.
    - Washburn, Charles G.
    - Whitmarsh, Theodore F.
    - Woodward, William
    - Yale Daily News
    - Young, Owen D.
- Personal and Memorabilia, Series II
  - Federal Reserve Bank Farewell Dinner, (December 20, 1926) (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Secretarial applications, (1926) (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Miscellaneous notes, receipts, souvenirs, etc. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Photostatic copy of Goebbels poster [January 27, 1928] (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Weekly Credit and Financial Summary, Series III
  - Index of Credit and Financial Summary, 1925 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Credit and Financial Summary, 1925 (Box 2, Folder 2-13)
  - Index of Credit and Financial Summary, 1926 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Credit and Financial Summary, January-Jun, 1926 (Box 2, Folder 15-20)
  - Credit and Financial Summary, July-Dec, 1926 (Box 3, Folder 21-26)
  - Index of Credit and Financial Summary, 1927 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Credit and Financial Summary, 1927 (Box 3, Folder 28-39)
  - Index of Credit and Financial Summary, 1928 (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Credit and Financial Summary, 1928-January-April 1929 (Box 4, Folder 41-56)
  - Credit and Financial Summary, May-December 1929-January-April 1930 (Box 5, Folder 57-68)
- Documents, Series IV
  - Lists of Documents issued by the Economic Service [incomplete] (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Doc. 1: Note by Monsieur Frere, November, 1924 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Doc. 2: The Returns of the Reichsbank (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Doc. 4: Balance Sheet of the Golddiskontbank (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Doc. 7: Public Opinion and 26% tax on German Exports (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Doc. 8: Proposals for Reduction of Taxes in the States and Communes (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Doc. 9: The Returns of the Reichsbank as on November 22, 1924 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Doc. 11: The Present Financial Situation, November, 1924 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Doc. 12: The Question of the Rentenbank-KreditAnstalt (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Doc. 13: Weekly Returns of the Golddiskontbank, November, 1924 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Doc. 14: Returns of the Reichsbank, November, 1924 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Doc. 15: Returns of the Reichshauptkasse November, 1924, December, 1924 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Doc. 16: The "Gold" Balance Sheets of the Four "D" Banks, December 1924 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Doc. 17: The Constitution of the Steel Trust (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Doc. 18: Foreign Capital in Germany (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Doc. 19: "America's Need for Foreign Investment", December, 1924 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Doc. 20: Weekly Balance Sheet of the Golddiskontbank, December, 1924 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Doc. 21: Debt of the Reich [Internal and External] October 31, 1924, December, 1924 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Doc. 22: Balance Sheet of the Rentenbank, November, 1924 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Doc. 23: The Returns of the Reichsbank, December, 1924 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Doc. 24: Short Note on Financial Relations Between the Reich, the States and the Communes (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Doc. 25: Dr. Schacht's Speech of December 15, 1924 to the Bankers (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Doc. 26: Weekly Balance Sheet of the Golddiskontbank, December, 1924 (Box 6, Folder 22-A)
  - Doc. 27: Distribution of the Charge imposed on German industry, December, 1924 (Box 6, Folder 22-B)
  - Doc. 28: Returns of the Reichsbank, December, 1924 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Doc. 29: Note on the Provisional Balancing of the Budget for the Financial Year 1924-1925 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Doc. 30: Returns of the Reichsbank as on December 1924 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Doc. 31: Weekly Balance Sheet of the Golddiskontbank, December 23, 1924 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Doc. 32: Proposed Nachtrag (Supplement) to the Budget for the Financial Year 1924=25, January, 1925 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Doc.33: Receipts of the Reich for November, 1924 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Doc. 34: Last Weekly Balance Sheet of the Golddiskontbank, January, 1925 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Doc. 36: Returns of the Reichsbank, January, 1925 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Doc. 37: Balance Sheet of the Rentenbank as on December 31, 1924, January, 1925 (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - Doc. 38: Returns of the Reichsbank, January 15, 1925 (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - Doc. 39: Prof. Cassel and Dr. Dernburg at Assoc. of Private Bankers in Germany, January, 1925 (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - Doc. 40: Taxation Receipts of Reich for December 1924, January, 1925 (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - Doc. 41: Movement of Funds of Reichshauptkasse December 1924, January, 1925 (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - Doc. 42: Returns of the Reichsbank, January, 23, 1925 (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - Doc. 43: German Criticisms of Lecture by Professor Cassel, January, 1925 (Box 6, Folder 37)
  - Doc. 44: Note by M. Gaillet - Billotteau on Deutsche Verkehrs - Kredit Bank, January, 1925 (Box 6, Folder 38)
  - Doc. 45: Note by M. Gaillet - Billotteau on Present Position and Conditions in Regard to Credit in Germany, January, 1925 (Box 6, Folder 39)
  - Doc. 46: Returns of the Reichsbank as on January 31, 1925, January, 1925 (Box 6, Folder 40)
  - Doc. 47: General Regulations of Ministry of Finance Governing the Acceptance of Foreign Credits by German Busness Men., February, 1925 (Box 6, Folder 41)
  - Doc. 48: Public Debt of the Reich as at December, 1924, February, 1925 (Box 6, Folder 42)
  - Doc. 49: Monthly Balance Sheet of the Rentenbank January, 1925, February, 1925 (Box 6, Folder 43)
  - Doc. 50: Returns of the Reichsbank as on February 7, 1925, February, 1925 (Box 6, Folder 44)
  - Doc. 51: Effects of Foreign credits upon German Economic Life, February, 1925 (Box 6, Folder 45)
  - Doc. 52: Returns of the Reichsbank as on February, 1925 (Box 6, Folder 46)
  - Doc. 53: Taxation Receipts of the Reich for the Month of January, 1925, February, 1925 (Box 6, Folder 47)
  - Doc. 54: Control of Foreign Loans Contracted by the States and Communes (Box 6, Folder 48)
  - Doc. 55: Movement of Funds at the Reichshauptkasse During January, 1925, February, 1925 (Box 7, Folder 49)
  - Doc. 56: Observations on the Ruhr Compensation, February, 1925 (Box 7, Folder 50)
  - Doc. 57: Reduction in the Discount Rate of the Reichsbank, February, 1925 (Box 7, Folder 51)
  - Doc. 58: The Returns of the Reichsbank, February, 1925 (Box 7, Folder 52)
  - Doc. 59: Draft Budget of the Reich for 1925-1926, February, 1925 (Box 7, Folder 53)
  - Doc. 60: Returns of the Reichsbank as on February 28, 1925, March, 1925 (Box 7, Folder 54)
  - Doc. 61: The Revalorisation of Debts in Paper marks, March, 1925 (Box 7, Folder 55)
  - Doc. 62: Monthly Balance-Sheet of the Rentenbank as on February 28, 1925, March, 1925 (Box 7, Folder 56)
  - Doc. 63: The Scheme for Organising the Rentenbank-Kreditastalt, March, 1925 (Box 7, Folder 57)
  - Doc. 64: Return of the Public Debt of the Reich as at January, 1925, March, 1925 (Box 7, Folder 58)
  - Doc. 65: Bill on the Beer Tax and the Tobacco Tax, March, 1925 (Box 7, Folder 59)
  - Doc. 66: The New Tax Bills of the Government, March, 1925 (Box 7, Folder 60)
  - Doc. 67: Note by M. Gaillet - Billotteau on the New Tax Proposals (Box 7, Folder 61)
  - Doc. 68: Movement of funds at the Reichauptkasse during the month of February, 1925, March, 1925 (Box 7, Folder 62)
  - Doc. 70: The Payment of Reparations and German Economy, March, 1925 (Box 7, Folder 63)
  - Doc. 71: Receipts of the Reich for the Month of February 1925, March, 1925 (Box 7, Folder 64)
  - Doc. 72: Estimated Expenditure on Staff By the Reich, the States, the Communes, the Reichsbann, the Reichspost and the State-Run Undertakings, March, 1925 (Box 7, Folder 65)
  - Doc. 73: Speech by M. Decamps on the Transfer Question, March 25, 1925 (Box 7, Folder 66)
  - Doc. 74: The Memorandum on the Loans of the Reich for 1924, March, 1925 (Box 7, Folder 67)
  - Doc. 75: The Public Banks, the Effect of their Activities on Credit and the Policy of the Reichsbank, March, 1925 (Box 7, Folder 68)
  - Doc. 76: The Situation of the Reichpost, April, 1925 (Box 7, Folder 69)
  - Doc. 77: Extension until September 30, 1925, of the Finanzausgleich, April, 1925 (Box 7, Folder 70)
  - Doc. 78: The New Bills on the Revalorisation of Paper Mark Debts, April, 1925 (Box 7, Folder 71)
  - Doc. 79: Law on the Payment of Official Salaries by Quarterly instalments, April, 1925 (Box 7, Folder 72)
  - Doc. 80: Law Concerning the Provisional Budget for the Financial Year 1925-1926, April, 1925 (Box 7, Folder 73)
  - Doc. 81: The Monthly Balance Sheet of the Rentenbank as on March 31, 1925, March, 1925 (Box 7, Folder 74)
  - Doc. 82: The Reichsbank Report for the Financial Year 1924, May, 1925 (Box 7, Folder 75)
  - Doc. 83: The Placing of German Mortgage Bonds on the American Market, April, 1925 (Box 7, Folder 76)
  - Doc. 84: Receipts of the Reich from Taxation for March, 1925 and for 1924-1925, April, 1925 (Box 7, Folder 77)
  - Doc. 85: The Movement of Funds at the Reichshauptkasse During the month of March 1925, April, 1925 (Box 7, Folder 78)
  - Doc. 86: Return of the Public Debt of the Reich as at February 28, 1925, April, 1925 (Box 7, Folder 79)
  - Doc. 87: The Employment of Public Funds in Private Business, May, 1925 (Box 7, Folder 80)
  - Doc. 88: The Monthly Returns of the Rentenbank April, 30, 1925, May, 1925 (Box 7, Folder 81)
  - Doc. 89: The Memorandum of the Government of the Reich on the Proposal to Tax Inflation Profits, May, 1925 (Box 7, Folder 82)
  - Doc. 90: Summary of a Speech Made in the Reichstag by Dr. Von Schlieben, May, 1925 (Box 7, Folder 83)
  - Doc. 91: Speech by Finance Minister Before The Budget Committee of the Reichstag, May, 1925 (Box 7, Folder 84)
  - Doc. 92: Revalorisation Bills in the Reichstag, May, 1925 (Box 7, Folder 85)
  - Doc. 93: German Government Memo on Staff Reductions in the Services of the Reich, May, 1925 (Box 7, Folder 86)
  - Doc. 94: The Public Debt of the Reich as at March 31, 1925, May, 1925 (Box 7, Folder 87)
  - Doc. 95: The Problem of Credit in Germany, May, 1925 (Box 7, Folder 88)
  - Doc. 96: The Report of the Deutsche Rentenbank for 1924, May, 1925 (Box 7, Folder 89)
  - Doc. 97: The Movement of funds at the Reichshauptkasse During the month of April 1925, June, 1925 (Box 7, Folder 90)
  - Doc. 98: Receipts of the Reich from Taxation for April 1925, June, 1925 (Box 7, Folder 91)
  - Doc. 99: Second Law on the Provisional Balancing of the Budget for the Financial Year 1925-1926, June, 1925 (Box 7, Folder 92)
  - Doc. 100: The Monthly Return of the Rentenbank as on May 31, 1925, June, 1925 (Box 7, Folder 93)
  - Doc. 101: Estimate of Business done on a basis of the Receipts from the Turnover Tax, June, 1925 (Box 7, Folder 94)
  - Doc. 102: Situation in Regard to the Public Debt of the Reich as at April 30, 1925, June, 1925 (Box 7, Folder 95)
  - Doc. 103: Movement of Funds at the Reichshauptkasse May, 1925, June, 1925 (Box 7, Folder 96)
  - Doc. 104: Transitional Tax Law, June, 1925 (Box 7, Folder 97)
  - Doc.105: The Credit Policy of the Reichsbank, July, 1925 (Box 7, Folder 98)
  - Doc. 107: Tax on Motor Vehicles, July, 1925 (Box 7, Folder 99)
  - Doc. 108: Table of Sums in Respect of Sinking Fund and interest Payable on the Various Items of the Public Debt, July 1, 1925-December 31, 1927, July 3, 1925 (Box 7, Folder 100)
  - Doc. 109: Provisional Results of the Census of The Population of the Reich, July, 1925 (Box 7, Folder 101)
  - Doc. 110: Position of the Public Debt of the Reich May 31, 1925, July, 1925 (Box 8, Folder 102)
  - Doc. 111: The Movement of Funds at the Reichshauptkasse June, 1925, July, 1925 (Box 8, Folder 103)
  - Doc. 112: The Returns of the Rentenbank June, 1925, July, 1925 (Box 8, Folder 104)
  - Doc. 113: Introduction to the Regulations for Deliveries in Kind for the use of French Buyers, July, 1925 (Box 8, Folder 105)
  - Doc. 114: Discount and Currency Policy of the Reichsbank, July, 1925 (Box 8, Folder 106)
  - Doc. 115: The Statistics of Unemployment in Germany, July, 1925 (Box 8, Folder 107)
  - Doc. 116: Law of July 16, 1925 on the Liquidation of Public loans, August, 1925 (Box 8, Folder 108)
  - Doc. 117: Tax Receipts of the Reich for June, 1925, August, 1925 (Box 8, Folder 109)
  - Doc. 118: The Establishment of the Rentenbank-Kretditanstalt, August, 1925 (Box 8, Folder 110)
  - Doc. 119: The Policy of the Reichsbank in Regard to Reserves, August 11, 1925 (Box 8, Folder 111)
  - Doc. 120: The Diskonto - Gesellschaft on the Transfer Problem, August, 1925 (Box 8, Folder 112)
  - Doc. 121: Statement by Geheimrat Kastl on the output and Markets of Germany, August, 1925 (Box 8, Folder 113)
  - Doc. 122: The Mining Industry of the Ruhr, August, 1925 (Box 8, Folder 114)
  - Doc. 123: Movement of Funds at the Reichshauptkasse July, 1925, August, 1925 (Box 8, Folder 115)
  - Doc. 124: The Debts of German Agriculture Before the War and Now, August, 1925 (Box 8, Folder 116)
  - Doc. 125: The Circulation of Bills in Germany (Box 8, Folder 117)
  - Doc. 127: Law of July 9 1925 on Foreign Borrowing by Communes, August, 1925 (Box 8, Folder 118)
  - Doc. 128: German Mortgage Banks Before the War and Now, August, 1925 (Box 8, Folder 119)
  - Doc. 129: Position of the Mining Industry in the Ruhr Memo from the Miners Union of Essen, August, 1925 (Box 8, Folder 120)
  - Doc. 131: Law on Income Tax of August 10, 1925, September, 1925 (Box 8, Folder 121)
  - Doc. 133: Law Concerning the Reciprocal Taxation Rights of the Reich, The Federal States and the Communes, September, 1925 (Box 8, Folder 122)
  - Doc. 134: Law in Amendment of the Finanzausgleich, September, 1925 (Box 8, Folder 123)
  - Doc. 135: The American Loan of the Rentenbank, September, 1925 (Box 8, Folder 124)
  - Doc. 136: Assessment Law of the Reich, September, 1925 (Box 8, Folder 125)
  - Doc. 137: Law in Amendment of the Taxes Dealing with the Movement of Capital, September, 1925 (Box 8, Folder 126)
  - Doc. 138: Balance Sheet of the Rentenbank as on August 1925, September, 1925 (Box 8, Folder 127)
  - Doc. 139: Law Concerning Taxes on Real and Personal Property and Successions, September, 1925 (Box 8, Folder 128)
  - Doc. 140: Corporation Tax Law of August 10, 1925, September, 1925 (Box 8, Folder 129)
  - Doc. 141: The Action of the German Government to Lower Prices, September, 1925 (Box 8, Folder 130)
  - Doc. 142: "Is the German Economy 'Passive?'" by Prof. Julius Hirsch, October, 1925 (Box 8, Folder 131)
  - Doc. 143: The Liquidation of the Mark Loans of the Reich, the States and The Communes, October, 1925 (Box 8, Folder 132)
  - Doc. 144: Movement of Funds at the Reichshauptkasse August, 1925, October, 1925 (Box 8, Folder 133)
  - Doc. 145: Tax Receipts of the Reich for the Month of August, 1925, October, 1925 (Box 8, Folder 134)
  - Doc. 146: Position of the Public Debt of the Reich as at June 30, July 31, and August 31, 1925, October, 1925 (Box 8, Folder 135)
  - Doc. 147: The Revalorisation of Private Claims Expressed in Paper Marks, October, 1925 (Box 8, Folder 136)
  - Doc. 148: The Balance Sheet of the Rentenbank September, 1925 (Box 8, Folder 137)
  - Doc. 149: Tax Receipts of the Reich - September 1925, October, 1925 (Box 8, Folder 138)
  - Doc. 150: Movement of Funds at Reichshauptkasse September, 1925, October, 1925 (Box 8, Folder 139)
  - Doc. 151: Balance Sheet of the Rentenbank as on October 31, 1925, November, 1925 (Box 8, Folder 140)
  - Doc. 152: Tax Receipts of the Reich for the Month of October, 1925, November, 1925 (Box 8, Folder 141)
  - Doc. 153: Movement of Funds At the Reichshauptkasse during the Month of October, 1925, November, 1925 (Box 9, Folder 142)
  - Doc. 154: Position of the Public Debt of the Reich as at September 30, 1925, November 25, 1925 (Box 9, Folder 143)
  - Doc. 155: Movement of Funds at the Reichshauptkasse During the month of November, 1925, December, 1925 (Box 9, Folder 144)
  - Doc. 156: Position of the Public Debt of the Reich as at October 31, 1925, December, 1925 (Box 9, Folder 145)
  - Doc. 157: Balance Sheet of the Rentenbank as on November 30, 1925, December, 1925 (Box 9, Folder 146)
  - Doc. 158: Tax Receipts of the Reich November 1925, December, 1925 (Box 9, Folder 147)
  - Doc. 159: The Gold Mortgage Bond Market, December, 1925 (Box 9, Folder 148)
  - Doc. 160: The Draft Budget of the Reich for the financial Year 1926-1927, January, 1926 (Box 9, Folder 149)
  - Doc. 161: The Finances of the Reich, January, 1926 (Box 9, Folder 150)
  - Doc. 162: The Position of Agriculturists in Germany, January, 1926 (Box 9, Folder 151)
  - Doc. 163: The Balance Sheet of the Rentenbank as on December 31, 1925, January, 1926 (Box 9, Folder 152)
  - Doc. 164: Movement of Funds at the Reichshauptkasse December, 1925, January, 1926 (Box 9, Folder 153)
  - Doc. 165: Tax Receipts of the Reich for the Third Quarter of the Financial Year 1925-1926 and for December, 1925, January, 1926 (Box 9, Folder 154)
  - Doc. 166: Position of the Public Debt of the Reich as at November 30, 1925, January, 1926 (Box 9, Folder 155)
  - Doc. 167: Balance Sheet of the Rentenbank as on January 30, 1926, January, 1926 (Box 9, Folder 156)
  - Doc. 168: Tax Receipts of the Reich for the month of January, 1926, February, 1926 (Box 9, Folder 157)
  - Doc. 169: Movement of Funds at the Reichshauptkasse January, 1926, February, 1926 (Box 9, Folder 158)
  - Doc. 170: The Exhaustion of Germany, March, 1926 (Box 9, Folder 159)
  - Doc. 171: Prussian Finances, March, 1926 (Box 9, Folder 160)
  - Doc. 172: Position of the Public Debt of the Reich December 31, 1925, March, 1926 (Box 9, Folder 161)